Michael Frauenholtz

Qualifications Summary

Full stack engineer with a passion for new technologies.

Worked as engineering lead for project team.

Trained in Agile and Lean software development.

Experienced in test-driven development.

Highly adaptable in quickly changing environments with strong orgazational and analytical skills.

Experience

Professional

January 2009 -April 2012 **Software Engineer**, Cerner Corporation, Kansas City, MO.

Design and implement Java RCP applications used to build and maintain client data

- O Trained several new engineers with coding best practices and team processes
- O Lead development teams of 5-6 people with 2 week iterations leveraging the agile methodology
- O Experience working on projects with 1 to 3 month timeline
- O Continuous product support post-release with enhancements and defect corrections by way of client interactions
- O Assisted in resolving 91% of support issues within a seven day timeframe by utilizing the Lean development process
- O Provided on-site support for client conversion in Santa Fe, NM

Internships

May 2008 -August 2008 Velocity Technical Intern, Cerner Corporation, Kansas City, MO.

Developed C++ technical skills working with framework used by many teams

- O Took direction from senior architect to implement major API change
- O Identified and fixed miscellaneous defects
- O Participated in bi-weekly design meetings with team in India

Education

August 2004 -December 2008 **B.S.** in Electrical Engineering, *University of Iowa*, Iowa City, IA, 3.32 GPA.

Computer Engineering sub-track

Minor in Mathematics, University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA.

Technical Qualifications

Java, JUnit, CCL/SQL, Oracle RDBMS, Hudson/Jenkins, Maven, Subversion, HTML, CSS, REST, Javascript, jQuery, node.js, backbone.js, mongodb, redis, Git, vim